<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<versions xmlns="versionSpace">
  <version launched="false" silent="true" version="1.6.LTS.19">
    <feature title="Change default launch option to running as jar">Use maven-shade-plugin to enable building shaded jar with all dependencies and adjust launch script to use jar as launch option and add HEAP_SIZE property to specify the -Xmx flag.</feature>
    <feature title="Add property to adjust or disable native buffer duration">Add NATIVE_AUDIO_BUFFER property to enable adjusting the duration of the native buffer used by jda-nas. Also allows to disable jda-nas by setting the value to 0.</feature>
    <feature title="Other improvements">Various minor improvements.</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" silent="true" version="1.6.LTS.18">
    <feature title="Use jda-nas to enable native audio streaming">jda-nas enables using native code to buffer and stream audio to reduce stuttering caused by garbage collection activity if supported by the current platform.</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" silent="true" version="1.6.LTS.17">
    <feature title="Improved queue widget">The queue widget now edits its message on reset rather than deleting and resending.</feature>
    <feature title="Improved login command">The output of the login command was improved and the link is deleted after usage to signal that it cannot be used anymore.</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" silent="true" version="1.6.LTS.16">
    <feature title="Improved command parsing">Improve how arguments and the argument prefix is handled</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.LTS.15">
    <feature title="Improved Spotify to YouTube redirection">The algorithm to find the best YouTube video for a given Spotify track has been improved. Note that you might not notice an improvement right away as the old results are still stored and will get updated gradually over the coming month.</feature>
    <feature title="Improved track loading error messages">Error messages shown when failing to load a track now reliably show the correct track when the queue has already skipped to the next track.</feature>
    <feature title="Updated lavaplayer dependency">Lavaplayer has been updated to 1.3.53 including a fix for YouTube videos failing to load sporadically (and thus by extension Spotify tracks) due to "no player block found" and a fix for missing video titles when playing a YouTube playlist.</feature>
    <feature title="Improved http server stability">Increased thread pool size for the http server to improve reliability under the now higher workloads.</feature>
    <feature title="Fix unavailable Spotify tracks">Fix unavailable Spotify tracks causing an error when loading a botify playlist by not including them.</feature>
    <feature title="Update YouTube API quota cost calculation">Update how the bot calculates YouTube API quota usage based on the changed quota costs.</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.LTS.11">
    <feature title="YouTube IP rotation">Added support for lavaplayer IP rotation to use different IP addresses for certain requests</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.LTS.4">
    <feature title="YouTube API quota usage adjustments">Tired of botify reaching the YouTube API quota limit and breaking all YouTube requests? So am I. Botify now calculates the approximate quota usage and stops using the YouTube API wherever possible in exchange for parsing the html response of YouTube pages using lavaplayer when the quota gets low.</feature>
    <feature title="Embed message formatting adjustments">Adjusted the layout of some embed messages to the new discord update.</feature>
    <feature title="Enabled JDA sharding">Added JDA sharding. This was originally intended as a feature for botify 2 but botify is going to reach 2500 guilds, the maximum number of guilds per WebSocket, before then.</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.LTS">
    <feature>this long-term-support version of botify 1.6 marks the end of development for botify 1 while development shifts to botify 2 featuring a new web client and improved queue management</feature>
    <feature>as an LTS release this version will continue to receive bug fixes even after botify 2 is released</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.5">
    <feature>final version of botify 1.6 that offers remaining improvements and optimisations</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.4">
    <feature>when searching a Spotify track, botify now automatically picks the best result based on likeness of the track names, track popularity and how popular each artist is in this guild; to get a selection of results like in previous versions you may use the "select" argument</feature>
    <feature>added album covers to the queue and "now playing..." widgets for Spotify tracks</feature>
    <feature>added a periodic task that resets playback settings and queues after an hour of inactivity to preserve resources and ensure long term stability</feature>
    <feature>other improvements and fixes</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.3">
    <feature>added synchronise command to sync an external playlist with a botify playlist</feature>
    <feature>added empty command to clear botify playlists</feature>
    <feature>added property to define the default text channel for bot messages</feature>
    <feature>added property to define timeout for automatic deletion of success and common error messages</feature>
    <feature>several improvements and fixes</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.2.1">
    <feature>fix issue with unavailable Spotify tracks in local playlists</feature>
    <feature>improve concurrent command handling and create abort command to interrupt long commands and cancel queued commands</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.2">
    <feature>**new command parser that is smarter at interpreting arguments**
      - makes using arguments less strict and inline arguments may now be used wherever you want in the command and they are treated as regular arguments with the input to their right as value
      - *meaning `insert track $to listName $at position` could now also be written `insert track $at position $to listName` or even `insert $to=listName $at=position track`*
      - enables using escape characters and quotes to escape meta characters e.g. `play $spotify \$trackname` or `play $spotify "$trackname"`
      - enables argument values containing whitespace by using quotes like `command $arg="some value"`</feature>
    <feature>**enabled selecting several options comma separated when asked a question**</feature>
    <feature>**added an option to select all options when asked a question by certain commands**</feature>
    <feature>**added property to customise argument prefix**</feature>
    <feature>**added monthly charts to charts command**</feature>
    <feature>**help command examples now use the custom prefixes**</feature>
    <feature>**upgrade to JDA 4**</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" silent="true" version="1.6.1.4">
    <feature>make Spotify redirect smarter</feature>
    <feature>add some handling for rare cases when PlaylistTracks have a null track</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" silent="true" version="1.6.1.3">
    <feature>update lavaplayer dependency to fix loading some YouTube videos</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" silent="true" version="1.6.1.2">
    <feature>enable silent updates</feature>
    <feature>fix export command</feature>
    <feature>fix Playable#matches</feature>
    <feature>improve upload command</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.1.1">
    <feature>improve and add new admin tools</feature>
    <feature>fix wrong behavior of the play / pause action when the bot left the channel</feature>
    <feature>minor improvements</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6.1">
    <feature>added charts command</feature>
    <feature>added properties to select the default source (Spotify, YouTube, local) when searching a track or list</feature>
    <feature>added property to toggle the auto pause feature</feature>
    <feature>various bug fixes and improvements</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.6">
    <feature>added customisable properties to change the color scheme or toggle playback notifications using the new property command</feature>
    <feature>added a whole new category of commands for bot admins to manage the bot</feature>
    <feature>reworked the permission command to manage several commands at once more easily</feature>
    <feature>permissions now also apply to widgets</feature>
    <feature>added support for Spotify URIs (e.g. spotify:track:3zLeZbjtoS5dS8qXt3274Y)</feature>
    <feature>reworked the help command to be more compact</feature>
    <feature>redesigned the queue widget and display enabled options on the "Now playing..." widget</feature>
    <feature>auto-pause when everyone leaves the voice channel</feature>
    <feature>reworked the "own" argument making it work for albums and support Spotify query syntax</feature>
    <feature>major rework of the code base providing several fixes and improvements</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.5.2">
    <feature>add new commands to manage playlists: move and insert</feature>
    <feature>make Spotify to YouTube redirect smarter</feature>
    <feature>allow preset names to start with command names without conflict</feature>
    <feature>improve traffic handling and limit how many commands can run concurrently per guild</feature>
    <feature>prevent spam of "Could not load track" messages</feature>
    <feature>spawning a new queue widget now deletes the old one</feature>
    <feature>fix old widget messages not being deleted</feature>
    <feature>raise bot name length limit to 20</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.5.1.2">
    <feature>fix presets containing a single quote</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.5.1.1">
    <feature>make preset search case insensitive</feature>
    <feature>fix commands not being parsed correctly due to case sensitivity</feature>
    <feature>fix bug in search command when searching for Spotify albums / playlists with less than 5 tracks</feature>
    <feature>correct some typos</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.5.1">
    <feature>command presets</feature>
    <feature>volume command</feature>
    <feature>customisable command prefix separate from bot name</feature>
    <feature>update notifications now show new features</feature>
    <feature>send a getting started message when a new guild joins</feature>
    <feature>add examples section to help command</feature>
    <feature>fix an issue where playlist tracks do not get played in the correct order</feature>
    <feature>fix an issue where the search command fails when displaying a short local playlist</feature>
    <feature>the "Now playing..." widget now shows the next track considering the repeat settings</feature>
    <feature>the queue command now shows the playback settings even when the queue is empty</feature>
    <feature>automatically unpause playback when playing a different track</feature>
  </version>
  <version launched="true" version="1.5.0.1"/>
  <version launched="true" version="1.5"/>
  <version launched="true" version="1.4.2"/>
  <version launched="true" version="1.4.1"/>
  <version launched="true" version="1.4"/>
  <version launched="true" version="1.3"/>
  <version launched="true" version="1.2"/>
  <version launched="true" version="1.1"/>
  <version launched="true" version="1.0"/>
</versions>